GIANNIS TORAKIS

Athens/Greece · +306982445915 johntor1995@gmail.com · LinkedIn

I am a Senior Software Engineer mainly focused on web applications. I have been a member of many teams in different projects in the banking sector (fintech), telecom companies, and software houses. The main technologies I've been working with are .NET (Core/Framework), Angular, and SQL (SQL Server/Oracle). I graduated from the Technical University of Crete, school of Electrical and Computer engineering, in 2019 (5-year integrated Master's). I also completed my second MSc in Biomedical Engineering at the University of Crete, School of Medicine.

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - CURRENT

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/TEAM LEAD, COSMOS BUSINESS SYSTEMS S.A.

My current position is a Senior Software Engineer/Team Lead in Cosmos Business Systems. My team is working for a client in the public sector, where we are responsible for the development and maintenance of welfare benefits. My main tasks are the development of new projects and implementation of change requests in existing ones, as well as the payment of each benefit every month. The latter is performed through stored procedures and packages on Oracle, which need to be executed, improved, and maintained every month. The core technologies used are .NET Framework 4.6.1 MVC and Oracle SQL. Before my current engagement with this client, I worked on another project of the public sector, where the used technologies were .NET 5, Angular 11 and PostgreSQL. The application was running on Docker and the deployment was on Kubernetes, where I was responsible for the CI/CD as well.

04/2022 - 09/2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, QUALCO

I worked as a Full-stack .NET Software Engineer for Qualco. The main tasks involved the development/improvement of the core company product (Qualco Collections), which was provided with custom functionality to each client. The platform was first developed in Windows Forms, and then migrated to .NET Core and Angular. A big part of the role was migration and integration tasks on SQL Server, where I developed stored procedures and packages for data import/management. I was also involved in the CI/CD process, by running pipelines and deploying releases on Azure Devops.

11/2021 - 04/2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, UNI SYSTEMS (ALPHA BANK GREECE)

I worked as a Full-stack .NET Software Engineer for Alpha Bank Greece. I worked in the Core Banking System, which is the heart of the bank's core operations. I was a member of the front layer team, which is built with Angular 10, .NET Core and SQL Server. Both REST and SOAP APIs were used for communication with other business layers. I worked with the latest Angular technologies, including RxJs and NgRx for state management. I was also involved in the architectural design of new projects. Finally, I worked on data integration/migration on SQL Server.

12/2020 - 11/2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, EPIC STUDIOS (ALPHA BANK GREECE)

(Outsourcing for UniSystems). I worked as a Full-stack .NET Software Engineer for Alpha Bank Greece. I worked in the Core Banking System, which is the heart of the bank's core operations. I was a member of the front layer team, which is built with Angular 10, .NET Core and SQL Server. Both REST and SOAP APIs were used for communication with other business layers. I worked with the latest Angular technologies, including RxJs and NgRx for state management. I was also involved in the architectural design of new projects.

11/2019 - 05/2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DELOITTE (NATIONAL BANK GREECE)

I worked as a Full-stack .NET Software Engineer for the National Bank of Greece. I was part of the team of the Internet Banking redesign project, where I came across various tasks. The main task was the development of web APIs in .NET Framework 4.6.1, with Angular 8 and MySQL Server. The APIs were implementing functionality about the retail bank accounts and cards. The coding pattern was test driven development (TDD). Amongst others, I also used Selenium and Specflow for behavioral driven development (BDD).

12/2018 - 11/2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, NOKIA

I worked as a software engineer intern in a team that developed internal tools (dashboards) for the management and monitoring of the main product. The project was multinational, and the team worked in an Agile pattern with two-week scrums. The dashboards were built in Python/Flask, Java Spring Boot, Angular and ReDis. The CI/CD was managed by jenkins pipelines. Machine learning was also involved, performing prediction and classification tasks.

03/2018 - 12/2018

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR INTERN, TUC (TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF CRETE)

I worked as a systems administrator in the network center of the Technical University of Crete. The main tasks were the installation, management and maintenance of computing systems and workstations, as well as the continuous update of the users' UI. I also provided support on hardware and software issues. Finally, I developed some scripts for penetration testing (sql injection).

EDUCATION

09/2020 - 05/2022

MSC IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, SCHOOL OF MEDICINE

Degree Thesis: Design of a multi-feature classification scheme for infant epileptic seizures GPA: 8.87

09/2014 - 09/2019

BSC IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF CRETE

Degree Thesis: Machine learning methods for the evaluation of biomolecular markers of pancreatic cancer and its correlation with embryogenesis GPA: 7.62

PUBLICATIONS

• Pancreatic cancer and its correlation with Embryogenesis: Pancreatic cancer and its correlation with Embryogenesis

SKILLS

- Ability to Work Under Pressure
- Decision

- Teamwork
- Creativity

HOBBIES

- Basketball
- Music
- Gym
- Travel

EXTRAS

• Completed military services